capetown.gov.za 2008-12-22

# City of Cape Town website privacy policy

This privacy policy sets out how the City of Cape Town uses and protects any information that you   
give the City when you use this website, knowingly or inadvertently.

The City of Cape Town is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should   
we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this   
website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy   
statement.

The City may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this   
page from periodically to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective   
from 1 April 2008.

What we collect

We may collect the following information from you: 

  * name and job title
  * contact information including e-mail address
  * demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
  * other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers  

What we do with the information we gather

We require this information to understand your needs and thus provide you with a better service.   
We may also use it:

  * for internal record keeping

  * to improve our products and services

  * to periodically send you news updates or other information that we think you may find   
interesting, using the e-mail address that you have provided for this express use

  * to periodially contact you for market research purposes. In this instance we would contact you either by e-mail, phone, fax or mail

  * to customise the website to better reflect your interests

### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised   
access or disclosure, we have established suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures   
to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

### How we use cookies

A cookie is a small file that asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you   
agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a   
particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web   
application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about webpage traffic and improve our website by tailoring it to our customers' needs. We only use this information for statistical analyses, whereafter the data is removed from our system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages   
you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any   
information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but   
you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent   
you from taking full advantage of the website.

### Links to other websites

Our website contains links to other websites that may be of interest to you. Once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not exercise any control over the other   
website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information   
that you provide whilst visiting such sites. As such sites are not governed by this privacy statement, you should exercise caution and read through their privacy statements. 

### Controlling your personal information

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

  * whenever you are asked to fill in a form on our website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
  * if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or e-mailing us at: CCTwebmaster@capetown.gov.za

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your   
permission or are required by law to do so. 

If you believe that any information we are holding about you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or e-mail us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any such   
incorrect information.
